so let's summarize the differences
between message-passing and shared
memory regarding who does communication
in message-passing the programmer is
responsible for figuring out who sends
and who receives the data in shared
memory the communication is happening
through shared variables in memory so
all of the actual sending of the data
back and forth is fully automatic the
programmer doesn't need to do that they
just store to memory and load from
memory and it is the responsibility of
the system to figure out when the data
gets sent in to whom as far as data
distribution is concerned that is which
course get to have which data in their
memory the program needs to manually do
this data distribution by explicitly
sending the data to the course that
needed in shared memory the system is
responsible for sending the data
wherever it's needed so the programmer
simply loads or stores to the data and
it is job of the hardware and the
software of the system to figure out
which data should be local where at what
time as far as how much hardware support
we need for message passing this support
is relatively simple we just need to
basically have a network card in the
network it can be a very fancy network
but it's just a network in contrast for
shared memory we need extensive hardware
support that automatically figures out
when to send data into home and where to
cash in etc etc so we will be spending a
large portion of the rest of this course
on just figuring out what these hardware
support needs to look like so as far as
the programmer is concerned the
programmer worries about two things
correctness and performance of their
program they want their program to be
correct and do as well as possible on
the available course in message passing
getting correctness is difficult because
you have to orchestrate everything
perfectly and you can get all sorts of
you know deadlock issues and wrong
distribution etc etc in shared memory
correctness is also not easy to get but
it's less difficult than with message
passing performance with message passing
is difficult to get but once you get
correctness performance is
not far away in contrast shared-memory
performance is very difficult to get and
the difference between correctness and
performance can be large so it might be
relatively easy to get our program to be
correct but its performance might not be
anywhere near good and then it might
take a lot more effort to get it to also
perform well so it message-passing
somehow by solving the correctness
problem you are also solving a large
part of the performance problem in
shared memory it's easier to get things
right but the effort to get it perform
well might be even more than with
message passing